Guide to the Charles David Marx Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles David Marx papers
1873-1942
SC0161
Marx, Charles David, 1858-1940
Marx, Charles David,, 1857-1939.
13 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
None.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charles David Marx was one of Stanford's original faculty, the Old Guard. He came to Stanford in 1891 as Professor of Civil Engineering and taught here until his retirement in 1923. He formed close friendships with his students and was affectionately known as Daddy Marx.
Marx was born in Ohio in 1857; during part of his youth he lived in Holland and Germany. He earned a bachelor's of civil engineering from Cornell University in 1878, after which he returned to Germany for further study. Before joining the Cornell faculty in 1884 he worked as an engineer on railroad and river projects in the eastern United States.
Marx's activities outside his Stanford work included serving on the Palo Alto Board of Trustees from 1896 to 1904 and 1908 to 1933; chairing the first State Water Commission after its organization in 1911; and serving as President of the American Society of Civil Engineers. After his retirement from teaching, Marx was a consultant on many hydraulic and sanitary engineering projects.
SCOPE NOTE
Marx's papers date from 1873 to 1942 and include correspondence, reports, research notes, manuscripts, drawings, financial records, clippings, minutes, reprints, and photographs. The papers primarily relate to engineering projects in which Marx was involved, largely dams and water systems in California, including projects at Stanford and Palo Alto. Other subjects include his years as student and lecturer at Cornell University; his civic work; and other professional activities.
Of note are minutes, correspondence, financial records, drawings, and reports of the Committee on Arch Dam Investigation of the Engineering Foundation, 1925-1933, which built an experimental single arch dam on the Stevenson Creek near Fresno, California; Marx was chairman of the Committee. Other persons represented in this series include H.W. Dennis, chief construction engineer of Southern California Edison Company, Fred A. Noetzli, construction engineer in charge of the dam, Willis A. Slater, engineer with the US Bureau of Standards, Alfred D. Flinn, director of the Engineering Foundation, and J.L. Savage of the US Dept. of the Interior.
The papers have been organized into the following series: I. Projects, II. Correspondence, III. Committee on Arch Dam Investigation, IV. Writings, V. Pipes and Pipe Flow, VI. Publications and Printed Matter, VII. Consultation Files, VIII. Other Professional Papers, and IX. Personal and Miscellaneous Papers.
Access Terms
Cornell University. -- General subdivision--Students.;; Dennis, H. W.; Engineering Foundation (U.S.).. Committee on Arch Dam Investigation..; Flinn, Alfred D.; Noetzli, Fred A.; Savage, J. L.; Slater, Willis A.; Stanford University. Department of Civil Engineering. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Arch dams.; Civil engineering.; Cyanotypes.; Dams--Design and construction.; Engineering drawings.; Engineering--Study and teaching.; Palo Alto (Calif.); Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- PROJECTS, SERIES I
  - Abeline, Kansas (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alpine Dam, Marin Country, CA (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Altoona, PA. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American-Consumnes Water Project (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American-Consumnes Water Project (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bay Cities Water Co. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bear Creek Dam (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beaver Creek Dam (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burlingame (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cache Creek (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cal. Gas & Electric (Big Bend) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cal. Water Service Corporation (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Camp Fremont, Menlo Park (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chatsworth Dam and Reservoir (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chatsworth Dam and Reservoir (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chatsworth Dam and Reservoir (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chatsworth Dam and Reservoir (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chatsworth Dam and Reservoir (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coast Valleys Gas & Electric Co. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Coast Valleys Gas & Electric Co. (cont.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Coast Valleys Gas & Electric Co. (cont.) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Colton, Ca. street paving (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Colusa - sewage and water supply (Folder 5)
  - Diamond Match Co., Chico - water supply (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - El Capitan Dam - correspondence, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - El Capitan Dam - report, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Eureka - sewage system (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Floriston Flume (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Forestry - misc. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gage Canal (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gilboa Dam, N.Y. - model (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Holly, Colo. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hetch Hetchy, Lake Eleanor, and Tuolumne River (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hotel Del Monte, Monterey, Ca. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Indian Wells Valley (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Irvine Conservation Dam (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Irvine Conservation Dam (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Islais Creek Incinerator (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Islais Creek Incinerator (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Kiowa, Kansas - waterworks (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lafayette Dam - correspondence, 1928-29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lafayette Dam - reports (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lake Cheesman Dam and Reservoir (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles - misc. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Madera Irrigation District (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Millbrae Water System (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Modesto and Turlock Irrigation Districts (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Monterey County Water Works - correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Monterey County Water Works - reports (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Morena Dam (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Water Co. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Natomas Consolidated of California (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Natomas Consolidated of California (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Natomas Consolidated of California (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - New York (City) - Board of Water Supply (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Northern Mexico Power Co. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Olinda Reservoir (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Osmeno Dam (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Palo Alto - lighting (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Palo Alto Municipal Power Plant (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Palo Alto Refuse Incinerating Plant (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto - sewer gaugings (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Palo Alto - storm sewers (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Palo Alto Water Works (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Palo Alto - wells (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Paradise Irrigation District (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pasadena, Ca. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pinole Dam (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Poderosa Mining Company (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Poulsen Wireless Corporation (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reclamation District No. 1000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Riverside, Ca. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sacramento River (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - St. Charles, Mo. Sewer System (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Salinas - sewer spec. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Salinas River Irrigation Investigation (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - San Diego - Lower Otay Dam (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - San Francisco (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - S.F. Auxiliary Water Supply (Cisterns) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - S.F. Bay Water & Rail Terminal Proposal (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - S.F. Bay Area - wells (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - S.F. Bay Area - Consensus Figures -, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - S.F. Earthquake, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - S.F. County Jail Specifications (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - S.F. County Jail Specifications (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - S.F. County Jail Specifications (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco Water Supply Investigations (one volume) (Box 7, Folder nf)
  - San Gabriel Dam (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - San Gabriel Dam (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - San Gabriel Dam (blueprints) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - San Gabriel Dam - blueprints (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - San Gabriel River - Report on Flood Control & Conservation... (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - San Gabriel River (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - San Gabriel River (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - San Gabriel River - State Div. of Water Rights. San Gabriel Investigation Progress Report... (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - San Gabriel River - State Div. of Water Rights. San Gabriel Investigation Progress Report... (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - San Gabriel Dam (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - San Gabriel Dam (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - San Gabriel Dam (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - San Jose boundaries (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - San Jose Water Co. - Buena Vista Plant (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - San Luis Obispo (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - San Mateo Water Works (also Palo Alto, Mayfield) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - San Mateo Wells (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sanderson & Porter (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sanderson & Porter (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Santa Clara (City) -Misc. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Spring Valley Water Co. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Univ. - Boiler Plant (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Univ. - Football field grandstands safety report (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Univ. - Hydraulic Lab Specifications (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Univ. - Lake Lagunita (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Univ. - Searsville (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Univ. - Searsville (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Univ. - Sewer Outfall & Water Supply (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Stanislaus River Project (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Stanislaus River - Middle Fork (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Stanislaus River - Sand Bar Flat (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Stockton - Water Supply (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Sutter Basin Project Report (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Sweetwater & San Jacinto Water Storage Problems (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Tacoma, Wa. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Census -, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Washington, Kansas sewers (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Univ. of Wisconsin (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Yale Quarry (Box 10, Folder 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, SERIES II
  - American Civic Association (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Civic Association (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Civic Association (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Cyanamid Company (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Woodlite Corporation (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Registration for Civil Engineers (completed applications) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Registration for Civil Engineers (completed applications) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ba - Bl (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bo - Bz (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ca - Cl (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Co - Cz (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Doolan, Jerome K. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Encyclopaedia of the Technological Sciences (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - I (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Jakobsen, B.F. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - K (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - L (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - M - N - O (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - P (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Reynolds, Leon R. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Rotary Process Refining Co. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - R (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Sa - Sh (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Si-Sz (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - T - U - V (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - W (Box 1, Folder 33)
- COMMITTEE ON ARCH DAM INVESTIGATION, SERIES III
  - Brackenridge, W.A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cain, Wm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Davis, R.E. - Financial statements (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Davis, R.E. - Reports (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Davis, R.E. - Reports (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Davis, R.E. - Reports (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Raymond (R.E.) - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Derleth, C. Jr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dennis, H.W. -, Jul-Dec 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dennis, H.W. -, Jul-Dec 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dennis, H.W. -, 1927-28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dennis, H.W. -, 1929-32 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dennis, H.W. -, Jan-Jun 1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, 1925-June 1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, July 1926- (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Flinn, A.D., 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, 1927-33 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Flinn, A.D. -, 1926-1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Flinn, A.D. - Reports (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hawgood, H. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Henny, D.C. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Markwart, A.H. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Comm. on Arch Dam Investigation (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Noetzli, F.A. - Reports (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Noetzli, F.A. - Reports (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Noetzli, F.A. - Reports (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Noetzli, F.A. - Reports (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Dec 1925-Dec 1926 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Dec 1925-Dec 1926 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Jan 1927-Jul 1928 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Jan 1927-Jul 1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Aug 1928-Dec 1929 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, Jan 1930-Apr 1931 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Noetzli, F.A. -, May 1931 - June 1932 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Savage, J.L. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Savage, J.L. - Reports (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Savage, J.L. - Reports (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Savage, J.L. - Reports (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Seabury, G.T. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Slater, W.A. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Slater, W.A. - Reports (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Slater, W.A. - Reports (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Slater, W.A. - Report of Test on Stevenson Creek Dam (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Slater, W.A. - Report of Test on Stevenson Creek Dam (cont.) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Swain, G.F. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Talbot, A.N. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- WRITINGS, SERIES IV
  - 60 Notebooks dating from (German, English), 1873 to 1884 (Box 1)
  - College papers - Cornell (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - College papers - Cornell (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - College papers - Cornell (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes - Cornell (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Course examinations - Cornell (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research notes (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dam of Concrete Piers and Steel Back (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Questions Relating to Outside Remunerative Work (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Consideration of Uplift as Affecting the Design of Masonry Dams (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Theoretical Dam Profile Which Considers Upward Pressures (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Engineering Education (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Flume Design (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript: Lectures on Elements of Engineering Design (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reprints - American Society of Civil Engineers (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reprints (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reprints (Box 3, Folder 5)
- PIPES AND PIPE FLOW, SERIES V
  - Pressure Pipe for Conveying Water (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Surges in Pipe Lines (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maximum efficiency in pipe lines (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sierra Pipe Line Studies (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sierra Pipe Line Studies (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Machine-made cement pipe (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Investigation of surge phenomena (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Wrought Iron Pipe vs. Steel Pipe (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Flow of water in open and closed conduits (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum, Table, & Diagram in Connection with the Discharge of water... (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Steel Pipe for Water Works (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Description of the Goldfields Water Supply (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Passaic Water Co. consumption (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pipe Laying Cost (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mabton Division Profile of pressure pipe (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Steel Penstock Pipe Lines (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lock & Bar Steel Pipe (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wooden Stave Pipe (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Reinforced Concrete Pipe (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Reinforced Concrete Pipe (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Riveted Steel Pipe (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Spacing of Steel Bands on Wooden Pipe Conduit (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Vertical Dipping Tank (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Collins Impact Tube & Manometer (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Vitrified Clay Pipe (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Life of pipes (Box 1, Folder 26)
- PUBLICATIONS AND PRINTED MATTER, SERIES VI
  - Pacific Service Magazine (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wilson Dam (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stony River Dam, W. VA. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Strange, W.L. - Earthen Dams (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Spokane, WA. Water Code (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Water Supply of San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco Water (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Public Works, Dec-22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Corthell, E.L. - Population of Great Cities: Growth and Density (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hill, Raymond A. - Graphics of Temporary Flood Storage (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ithaca, N.Y. Water Supply (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Schulze, Oscar - Notes on the Belubula Dam (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Smith, W.F. - Kensico Reservoir (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Taylor, T.U., The Austin Dam (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Western Waterworks (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Contract forms (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - California Railway and Power Co. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Daily Palo Alto Times, Wednesday, November 2, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Standards - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - City of Palo Alto Thirty-second Annual Report: Year Ending June 30, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CONSULTATION FILES, SERIES VII
  - Montecito County (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Montecito County (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Oakland Harbor, Jun-Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Oakland Harbor, Jun-Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Oakland Harbor, Jun-Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oakland Harbor, Jun-Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Oakland Harbor, Jun-Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Oakland Harbor (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Oakland Harbor (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Oakland Harbor, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oakland Harbor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Oakland Harbor, Nov 1924-Apr 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Oakland Harbor, Nov 1924-Apr 1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Oakland Harbor, Nov 1924-Apr 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Oakland Sewage Commission (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Oakland Sewage Commission (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Oakland Sewage Commission (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Peninsula Water Conference Committee (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Portland Cement Association (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Public Works Engineering Corp. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Public Works Eng. Corp. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Regional Planning Assoc. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reno Sewer System (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reno Sewer System (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rhodes, J.E. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rhodes, J.E. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Rhodes, J.E. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - San Diego Water Co. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - S.F.-Alameda Co. Bridge Commission (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - S.F.-Alameda Co. Bridge Commission (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - S.F. City Engineer - report pertaining to Hetch-Hetchy project, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - San Gabriel Flood Control (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - San Gabriel Flood Control (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - San Gabriel Flood Control (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Salt Water Barrier (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Salt Water Barrier (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - San Jose - Alum Rock Dam (Box 3, Folder 13)
- OTHER PROFESSIONAL PAPERS, SERIES VIII
  - California Military Welfare Commission (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - War Camp Community Service (Camp Fremont) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Klamath River Study Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Klamath River Study Committee (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Mediation (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - State Water Commission of California (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - California Board of Control - Applications (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - California Board of Control - Minutes & financial statements (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - California Board of Control - Water Commission Bill (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - California Board of Control - Transcripts of testimony (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Palo Alto Board of Trustees, Marx's terms:, 1896-1904, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - World Engineering Congress (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - World Engineering Congress (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - World Engineering Congress (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Legislative proposals (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Deer Creek Dam - Student papers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Engineering students' post-graduate work records (D. C. Brewer, Earl D. Brown, E. G. Brua) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sanitary Engineers - Curriculum (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - References: Sanitary Engineering (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notes on water works distribution system, possibly for Monterey County (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Civil Service Exam, Phillipine service, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Phillipines - Misc. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letter to Dr. Emilio Civit, 19-Jan-03 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Memo related to the Examination of the Dredge Plant at West Memphis, 17-Jan-03 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bill - HR28825 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Contra Costa Water Co. vs. City of Oakland (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Herre, O. - Design and Construction of Steel Tanks (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wing, C. B. - Investigation of Stability of Buttress Dam (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Parsons, The Analytical Determination of Dimensions of...Masonry Dams (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Worthington, R.S., Report on the Flow of Underground Water (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Fecht, H. - untitled article (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Translation of a Portion of an Article by Prof. Phillip Forchheimer... (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Jakobsen, B.F., Stresses in Gravity Dams (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Clavenad, C. A Study of Reservoir Dams, translated by R.E. McDonnell (Box 2, Folder 23)
- PERSONAL AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS, SERIES IX
  - Beebee, R.A. - Oakland Public Service Commission (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beebee, R.A. - Feather River (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beebee, R.A. - Harbor Engineer (application) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beebee, R.A. - Higgins Project (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beebee, R.A. - Klamath River (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beebee, R.A. - East Bay Water Co. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beebee, R.A. - Lincoln, Ca. Sewerage System (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Proposed Post Office for the City of South Pasadena (drawing) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Oakland map (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous forms (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Misc. - Personal papers (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (cyanotypes of bridges) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (cyanotypes of bridges) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs (cyanotypes of bridges) (Box 1, Folder 15)